

RESEARCH SCIENTIST, TOYOTA CENTRAL R&D LABS., INC.

Koraku Mori Bldg 10F, Koraku 1-4-14, Bunkyo, Tokyo, 1120004, Japan.

■ keisuke.otaki.jp@gmail.com | 希 https://researchmap.jp/cocomoff/?lang=english | ᡚcocomoff | tococomoff | 對 @cocomoff

Summary

Keisuke Otaki received the B.E. degree in Engineering (Computer Science) in 2011 from Kyoto University, Japan. He also received his Ph.D. degree in Informatics from Kyoto University in 2016. He was a visiting doctor course student at the University of Bonn and Fraunhofer IAIS from 2013 to 2014 during his Ph.D. course. He was also an research fellow of JSPS from 2016. He then joined the current position.

Statements on Recent Work: I'm working at Toyota Central R&D Labs., Inc. in Japan (whose headquater is located in Aichi, and its branch office is in Tokyo). Recent targeting international conferences of our team: AAAI, IJCAI, ITSC, AAMAS, ICAPS, etc. My recent research topics are

- combinatorial optimization (both problem modeling and solving) for applications such as path-planning, vehicle operations, ridesharing, multi-agent path-findings, etc. (60%),
- utilizing discrete data structures (e.g., decision diagrams, graphs, succinct data structures) in optimization and machine learning (30%), and
- developing spatio-temporal data mining algorithms (10%)

Note: TCRDL is a research institute in the Toyota group, whose mission statement is doing advanced researches and development for the modern and sustainable transportation system. We often do collaborative research with other companies in the Toyota group (e.g., Toyota Motor Corp., Denso, etc.) and also with other universities or institutes.

Education

Graduate School of Informatics, Kyoto University

Kyoto, Japan

Ph.D in Informatics, and M.S. in Informatics

Apr. 2011 - Mar. 2016

- Ph.D Thesis: Algorithmic Approaches to Pattern Mining from Structured Data
- Supervisor: Akihiro Yamamoto, Committee: Akutsu Tatsuya, Kashima Hisashi

Faculty of Engineering, Kyoto University

Kyoto, Japan

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Mar. 2011 - Apr. 2009

National Institute of Technology, Fukui College

Fukui, Japan

Quasi-undergraduate course of Engineering

Mar. 2009 - Apr. 2004

Research Experiences_

Toyota Central R&D Labs., Inc.

Aichi and Tokyo, Japan

RESEARCHER

Jan. 2017 - present

Japan Society for the Promotion of Science

Kyoto, Japan Apr. 2014 - Mar. 2016

RESEARCH FELLOW (DC2)

• Project: Studies on mining from structured data and their visualization

- Supervisor: Dr. Akihiro Yamamoto
- Research topics: Pattern mining, Visualization, Graph-structured data

Fraunhofer IAIS and University of Bonn

Sankt Augstin, Germany

VISITOR (VISITING STUDENT)

Mar. 2013 - Feb. 2014

- · Project: Studies on mining algorithms from structured data and methods for preserving privacy, particularly for graph-structured data
- · Supervisor: Dr. Tamás Horváth
- Research topics: Mining algorithms, Graph pattern mining, Probabilistic algorithms

		- 11	. •
Se	ected	Publi	cations

These are selected papers. See my researchmap page for details.

Multi-agent Path Planning with Heterogeneous Cooperation

K. Otaki, S. Koide, K. Hayakawa, A. Okoso, T. Nishi

IEEE ICTAI2019 Nov. 2019

Multi-Agent Path Finding with Priority for Cooperative Automated Valet Parking

A. Okoso, K. Otaki, T. Nishi

IEEE ITSC2019 Oct. 2019

NERO: Hierarchical-approximated Rebalancing Optimization for Mobility on Demand

T. Nishi, S. Koide, K. Otaki, A. Okoso

arXiv 2019

arXiv:1906.10835, 2019

Cooperative Routing with Heterogeneous Vehicles

K. Otaki, S. Koide, A. Okoso, T. Nishi

AAMAS2019 May. 2019

Traffic Signal Control Based on Reinforcement Learning with Graph Convolutional

Neural Nets

Nov. 2018

Annals of Mathematics and Artificial

T. Nishi, K. Otaki, K. Hayakawa, T. Yoshimura

IEEE ITSC2018

Learning Concepts and Their Unions from Positive Data with Refinement Operators

Intelligence

2017

S. Ouchi, T. Okayama, K. Otaki, R. Yoshinaka, A. Yamamoto

DOI:10.1007/s10472-015-9458-6.

IPSJ TOM

Periodic Pattern Mining with Periodical Co-occurrences of Symbols К. Отакі, А. Үамамото

2016

vol.9(1), pp.33-42, 2016.

К. Отакі, А. Үамамото

Periodical Skeletonization for Partially Periodic Pattern Mining

DS2015

Oct. 2015

Awards

DOMESTIC

2015

2019 Poster Award, JAWS2019 Hiroshima, Japan

2016 IPSJ Yamashita SIG Research Award, IPSJ

Best Presentation Award, IPSJ SIG-MPS #105

Japan Kitami, Japan

Extracurricular Activity

Machine Learning Summer School 2015

Kyoto, Japan

THE WEB MASTER, A LOCALIZER, AND A LOCAL ARRANGEMENT MEMBER

- Sep. 2015

Trends in Machine Learning, A Workshop at Kyoto University

A MEMBER OF THE ORGANIZATION TEAM

Mar. 2014

Kyoto, Japan

Machine Learning Summer School 2012

Kyoto, Japan - Sep. 2012

THE WEB MASTER AND A LOCAL ARRANGEMENT MEMBER

The Kyoto School Project

Kyoto, Japan

A WEB DEVELOPER

2011-2012

Arranged and created electrical archive Web pages for famous philosophers worked in Kyoto University

Projects at TCRDL

(Tentative) Optimization for Social Transportation System

Bunkyo, Tokyo

MULTI-AGENT SYSTEM PROGRAM, SOCIAL-SCIENCE RESEARCH DOMAIN

Jan. 2020 - present.

Combinatorial Optimization for Intelligent Transportation Systems

Bunkyo, Tokyo

MULTI-AGENT SYSTEM PROGRAM, DATA-ANALYTICS RESEARCH DOMAIN

Apr. 2019 - Dec. 2019

- · Worked on cooperative transportation systems and did research on multi-agent systems (MAS).
- Did large-scale numeraical experiments of combinatorial optimizations for multiple vehicles.
- Developed optimization methods using data structures for MAS.

Learning and Optimization for Intelligent Transportation Systems

Nagakute, Aichi

MULTI-AGENT SYSTEM PROGRAM, DATA-ANALYTICS RESEARCH DOMAIN

Feb. 2018 - Mar. 2019

- Learned fundations on mathematical programmings and implementations by Gurobi.
- Modeled and did experiments on recent transportation systems such as ride-sharing, transfer, vehicle routing, etc.
- Proposed a new mathematical model for heterogeneous vehicles.

Reinforcement Learning for Transportation System and Maintanence Systems

Nagakute, Aichi

INTELLIGENT SYSTEM CONTROL PROGRAM, DATA-ANALYTICS RESEARCH DOMAIN

Oct. 2017 - Jan. 2018

- Surveyed and tested the maintenance domain for RL.
- Worked on the warm-up problem of RL, particularly on the routing domain.

Reinforcement Learning for Transportation System

Nagakute, Aichi

DATA SCIENCE PROGRAM, DATA-ANALYTICS RESEARCH DOMAIN

Apr. 2017 - Sep. 2017

- · Learned fundamental concepts on Reinforcement Learning (RL) and Deep RL (DRL) via OpenAl gym.
- Worked on proposed RL applications for transportation systems, including routing and traffic signal control.

Learning and Inference System

Nagakute, Aichi

LEARNING AND INFERENCE PROGRAM, DATA-ANALYTICS RESEARCH DOMAIN

Feb. 2017 - Mar. 2017

· Surveyed Topological Data Analysis (TDA) and program developments for computing persistent diagrams for 3D protein structures.